a Web front end server might be in the DMZ,
but it might retrieve data from a database server
that is on the other side of the firewall.
For example,
you may have a network where you manage your client's personal information,
and even if the data is encrypted or obfuscated by cryptography,
you need to make sure the network is
completely segregated from the rest of the network,
with some secure switches that only an authorised individual has access to.
Only authorised personnel can control the firewall settings and control
the traffic between the Web server and the internal network.
For example,
in a hospital or a doctor's office,
you would have a segregated network for the patient information and billing,
and on the other side would be the electronic medical records.
If they are using a Web based application for medical record services,
they would have a demilitarised zone or segmented areas
and perhaps even behind the firewall.
They have their own specified server to protect
the critical information and keep it segregated.
It is worth noting at this point that
while this course will not explore the specifics,
some networks use a Web application firewall WAF rather than AD MZ network.
The WAF has an internal and an external connection, like a traditional firewall,
with the external traffic being filtered by
the traditional or next generation firewall.
First,
it monitors all traffic encrypted or not
from the outside for malicious behaviour before
passing commands to a Web server that may be internal to the network.